( BELL RINGING )
BARTENDER : Last orders , please .
- LIZ : Shaun . - Yeah ?
- Do you see what I 'm saying ? - Yeah , totally .
I know he 's your best friend , but you do live with him .
I know .
It 's not that I don 't like Ed . Ed , it 's not that I don 't like you .
It 's all right .
- It 'd just be nice if we could ... - Fuck .
- ... spend a bit more time together . - Bollocks .
- Just the two of us . - Cock it .
It 's just with Ed here , it 's no wonder I always bring my flatmates out ,
and then that only exacerbates things .
- What do you mean ? - Well , you guys hardly get on , do you ?
- No , what does " exacerbate " mean ? - It means to make things worse .
Right , right .
Well , I mean , it 's not that I don 't like David and Di , you know .
- Guys , it 's not that I don 't like you . - BOTH : It 's all right .
And it 's not that I don 't want to spend time with you , ' cause I do .
It 's just Ed doesn 't have too many friends .
Can I get any of you cunts a drink ?
- Anybody ? - BOTH : No , thank you .
I know friends are important to Shaun ,
but you do actually have to set some quality time aside for yourselves .
Yeah , I mean Daffs is always taking me to see these listed buildings ,
and , you know , I 'm always dragging him to the theater .
I 'm not so hot on theater .
DIANNE : Well , how about a nice meal ? It 's your anniversary soon , isn 't it ?
- It was last week . - Oh . Did you do anything special ?
- We came here . - ED : Shaun . Hog lumps .
Shaun , what I 'm trying to say is I need something more ,
more than spending every night in the Winchester .
I want to get out there and do more interesting stuff .
I want to live a little . I want you to want to want to do it , too .
Listen to me . I 'm beginning to sound like your mum .
Not that I 'd know what she sounds like .
- You still haven 't met his mum ? - Not yet .
Don 't you get along with your mum , Shaun ?
No . It 's not that I don 't get on with her ...
- Are you ashamed by your mum , Shaun ? - No , I love my mum .
- I love his mum . - SHAUN : Ed !
- She 's like butter . - Ed !
- BOTH : Shaun ! - Guys .
- Shaun . - Liz .
Look , I understand what you 're trying to say , okay , and I agree .
We should get out there . We 'll start tomorrow .
All right , I 'll book a restaurant , you know , the place that does all the fish .
Just the two of us . Things will change , I promise .
Really , Shaun ?
( BELL RINGING )
BARTENDER : Time , gentlemen .
MAN ON JUKEBOX : ( SINGING ) This town is coming like a ghost town
LIZ : Shaun ?
( BELL RINGING )
MALE VOICE ON TV : Player two has entered the game .
Haven 't you got work ?
MALE VOICE ON TV : Player two has left the game .
You do know the front door was open again last night .
- I 'm not saying it was you . - I know , man .
- I 'm saying it was Ed . - Right .
I can 't live like this .
I mean , just look at the state of it .
- We 're not students anymore . - Pete , just ...
I mean , it 's not like he even brings any real money into the house .
- Well , he brings a bit . - What , dealing drugs ?
Oh , he sells a bit of weed every now and again , you know .
You 've sold puff .
Yeah , once . At college . To you .
Well , look , I 've known him since primary school , you know .
I like having him around , he 's a laugh .
What , because he can impersonate an orangutan ? Fuck-a-doodle-doo .
Oh , leave him alone .
All right , I admit he can be pretty funny on occasion .
Like that time we stayed up all night drinking Apple Schnapps
and playing Tekken 2 .
Oh , yeah .
When was that ?
That was five years ago . When 's he going home ?
Hey , man , listen ... Top left .
- I was gonna say ... Reload . - I 'm on it .
- Since ... Nice shot . - Thanks .
( MOBILE RINGING )
Two seconds .
- You all right , Noodle ? - Hello , mate , got anything ?
- No , man . - But Eball says you was holding .
- I ain 't got nothing . - What ? You ain 't got nothing at all ?
ED : I 've only got a Henry meself . All right , laters .
- Listen ... - PETE : Ed ,
since you 're not working at the moment ,
- could you please clean up a bit ? - ED : Yep .
And if you play the answer machine ,
could you take down everyone 's messages , not just your own ?
Yep .
It 's not that taxing , is it ?
Writing something on a little scrap of paper ?
- Nope . - Right .
( MOBILE RINGING )
- PETE : Dom , hi ... - Come on , it was pretty funny .
- Will you do what he said though ? - I ain 't doing nothing for him .
Well , do it for me , then .
I 'm sorry , Shaun .
- It 's all right . - No , no . I 'm sorry , Shaun .
Oh !
Oh , my God , that 's rotten .
I 'll stop doing them when you stop laughing .
( PHONE RINGING )
I am not laughing , I 'm going .
- Get that . - You get it .
( RINGING )
LIZ : Hello , Shaun , it 's me .
Look , I 'm gonna be a bit tied up today ,
So when you book the table , can you make it 8 : 00 rather than 7 : 00 ?
I 'll try you at work . Bye , bye , bye .
( BEEPING )
Hey ! You 're dead .
- Spare some change , please , mister ? - Yeah .
( COINS FALLING )
( HONKING )
MAN : Watch out . Are you blind ?
MAN ON RADIO : The American deep space probe Omega Six ,
due to return to earth this weekend ,
has unexpectedly re-entered Earth 's atmosphere over south-east England
and broken apart over what 's believed to be a populated area .
Nelson ?
Hello , my friend . No beer today ?
No , it 's a bit early for me .
SHAUN : Gather round , everyone . Gather round , please .
Gather round .
Now , as well as Mr. Sloman being off today ,
I 'm afraid Ash is feeling a little bit under the weather .
- So , I will be taking charge , as the ... - Oldest .
Senior Staff Member .
So , if we can all just pull together , I know that ...
( MOBILE RINGING )
Hello ? Hello , mate .
- Noel ... - I was totally munted last night .
Yeah , I spoke to him . He 's only got Henry .
- All right , mate . Laters . - MAN : Laters .
- Continue . - Thank you .
As Mr. Sloman always says , " There 's no ' I ' in team but there is an ' I ' in pie .
" In ... There 's an ' I ' in meat pie . "
The anagram of " meat " is " team . " I don 't know what he 's talking about .
Look , that 's it . And , Noel , phones off , yeah ? It 's not a social gathering .
All right , keep your hair on , Grandad .
Hey , hey , whoa . I 'm 29 for Christ 's sakes . How old are you ? 20 ? 21 ?
- Seventeen . - Hey , well ...
Look , I know you don 't wanna be here forever .
I got things I wanna do with my life .
When ?
You got red on you .
( MOBILE RINGING )
NOEL : Hello , mate .
This one comes with a basic , sort of , digital package .
You 've got your lifestyle channels there , a bit of Trisha .
You 've got entertainment ... I don 't know what that is .
News . All the basic news channels .
FEMALE REPORTER : ... believed to be caused by exposure ...
- NOEL : Shaun . - Yeah , I 'm with customers .
It 's your dad .
He 's not my dad , he 's my stepdad .
Philip .
Shaun .
I trust you haven 't forgotten about tomorrow .
- No . - Your bi-monthly visit .
No , I haven 't forgotten .
Perhaps you could bring the flowers you forgot to bring Barbara on Mother 's Day .
I was gonna .
And not a cheap posy from a garage forecourt .
I wasn 't gonna .
Well , we look forward to seeing you tomorrow , then .
- Okay . - You 've got red on you .
I thought you said this wasn 't a social gathering ?
What ?
How comes you 're allowed to speak to your dad ?
A , he 's not my dad , okay ? He 's my stepdad .
And B , it was an emergency .
What , like buying your mum some flowers ?
Noel , no matter what you might think , okay ,
I do not find it difficult to keep my work and my social life separate .
MAN : Shaun . It 's Liz for you .
- Hello . - LIZ : Hello , it 's me .
- Hello . - Just quickly , did you get my message ?
Yep .
- Oh , so it 's all okay , then ? - Yep .
800 , the place that does all the fish ?
Yeah .
Oh , cool , well , that 's great . Just ring me later .
- Goodbye , Liz . - Bye . Bye , bye , bye .
Liz from Head Office . It 's nothing to panic about .
Sir ? Sir ?
Sorry . They 're for my mum .
" To a wonderful mum " or " Pow ! Super Mum " ?
- The first one . - Right .
( HORN BLARING )
- Oh , my God ! - Jesus !
- Shaun ! - Yvonne .
- How are you doing ? - Surviving .
So , are you living round here ?
- Um , yeah , are you ? - Yeah , I 've just bought a place , actually .
- Bought ? - I know , bit grown up , eh ?
- Are you still with ... - Liz .
That 's great . Glad somebody made it .
How long 's that been now ?
It 's three years ago last week , actually .
Did you do anything special ?
Well , we 're going out for a meal tonight , actually .
Oh , anywhere nice ?
Yeah .
Come on !
( PHONE RINGING )
- Are you gonna thank me , then ? - For what ?
Tidying up .
- Well , it doesn 't look that tidy . - Well , I had a few beers when I finished .
MAN ON PHONE : Hello , Fulci 's . Can you hold , please ?
Yeah .
- Do you want your messages ? - What ?
Well , your mum rang about going round tomorrow night .
And then Liz rang about the two of you eating out tonight .
And then your mum rang back to see if I wanted to eat her out tonight .
- What ? - Hello , Fulci 's .
Yeah , hi .
I know this is really short notice and everything ,
but could you possibly do me a table for two for tonight at about 8 : 00 ?
No , sorry , we just gave away the last table .
God !
Wasn 't true about your mum .
What am I gonna do ? Where are we gonna go ?
- The Winchester . - Don 't be stupid ! They don 't do food .
There 's a Breville out back . John 'll do you a toastie .
Ed , this is serious !
( PHONE RINGING )
- Hello . - LIZ : Hello , it 's me .
- Hello . - So , what 's the plan , then ?
Yeah , there 's been a bit of a mix-up with the table , babe .
What do you mean ?
They 're ... They 're full up .
But I thought you said it was all okay !
Yeah .
You didn 't book it , did you , Shaun ?
- No . - So , what is the plan , then ?
The Winchester ?
( DIAL TONE BUZZING )
( DOORBELL BUZZING )
DIANNE ON SPEAKER : Hello .
Dianne , can you let me in , please ?
I 'm not sure this is the best time , Shaun .
Oh , come on .
DAVID : Lizzie doesn 't want to see you , Shaun . Go away .
- Just open the door ! - She doesn 't want to see you , Shaun .
What do you want me to do ? Do you want me to go ...
Do you want me to climb up the wall , come through the window ? ' Cause I will .
DAVID : You 're not coming in .
- I ... All right . See you in a minute . - Don 't ...
( SHAUN GRUNTING )
( BUZZING )
SHAUN : Hi , it 's me again .
Liz , can we just talk about this ? You know , let 's go out .
- What , to the Winchester ? - Well ... Do you want to ?
- LIZ : No , I don 't fucking want to ! - Okay . I just thought , you know ...
It 's not the only place in the world , Shaun !
Well , we could go to The Shepherd 's , then , they do Thai in there now .
I 'm going out with David and Di .
SHAUN : Well , let 's all go together . LIZ : What , you hang out with my friends ?
- Sorry , a failed actress and a twat ? - SHAUN : Well , that 's harsh .
LIZ : Your words . SHAUN : I did not call Dianne a failed actress .
Let 's just go out , you know .
Let 's just go out somewhere and have a laugh .
Things 'll be fine , I promise .
You promised you 'd stop smoking when I did .
- What ... - You promised you 'd go back to the gym !
- I ... - You promised you 'd try drinking red wine
- instead of beer ! - Well ...
You promised you 'd come on holiday with me .
- We went to Greece , didn 't we ? - We met in Greece .
- At a rave . - It 's just not the same .
- You promised things would change . - You promised you 'd get us free cable .
- I 'm working on that . - Okay .
Well , I can give up smoking . I can give up whenever I want .
Look , see . Don 't need them .
- What was the next one ? - It 's not enough , Shaun .
Basically , I 'd say your nine lives are up , Shaun .
Get fucked , four-eyes !
Why don 't you go out with her , you love her so much ?
What do you mean by that ?
MALE REPORTER ON TV : The devastation really is extensive . It really is a total mess .
I don 't know what he meant by that .
SHAUN : Got you these .
To a wonderful mum ?
Oh ! Yeah .
Yeah , that 's because I thought it would be funny
because of what you said last night about me , you know ,
you don 't wanna be my mum and that , and it 's just a little joke .
It 's something I just thought of , spur of the moment .
- They 're for your mum , aren 't they ? - Yeah .
Smooth .
Look , if I don 't do something ,
I 'm gonna end up in that pub , every night , for the rest of my life ,
like those other sad old fuckers , drinking myself to death ,
wondering what the hell happened .
What do you mean , " Do something " ?
Fuck her !
You got your pint . You got your pig snacks . What more do you want ?
Oh . Your favorite monkey ?
Shall I do Clyde ?
( IMITATING ORANGUTAN )
See , I knew you 'd get over her .
( SOFT MUSIC PLAYING ON JUKE BOX )
- Who the hell put this on ? - It 's on random .
Ah , for fuck 's sake . John , yes , please , mate .
You know what we should do tomorrow ?
Keep drinking . We 'll have a Bloody Mary first thing .
Have a bite at the King 's Head , couple at The Little Princess ,
we 'll stagger back here and bang , we 're back at the bar for shots .
How 's that for a slice of fried gold ?
- No . - Come on , man .
Talk to me .
She said if she stayed with me , she 'd end up coming in here , every night ,
for the rest of her life , like these sad old fuckers , drinking herself to death ,
wondering what the hell happened .
That is harsh . These are rich , interesting characters .
Like who ?
Snakehips . Always surrounded by women . He 's a bigamist .
Strangled his first wife with a draught excluder .
And he invented the mobile disco .
Well , what about her , then ?
Cockacidal maniac .
She 's an ex-porn star . She 's done it all .
They say she starred in the world 's first interracial hardcore loop .
Café au Lait .
( MOANS )
Pour vous .
Yeah . What about John , then ?
ED : He 's North London Mafia .
( SHAUN SCOFFS )
ED : It 's true , Big Al says so .
Yeah , well , Big Al also says dogs can 't look up .
Think about it . Handy with a blade . Gruff demeanor .
Bernie , the trophy wife . He 's connected .
Why do you think there 's a rifle above the bar ?
SHAUN : ' Cause the pub 's called the Winchester .
Exactly .
See , you don 't need Liz to have a good time .
Oh , Ed , don 't , man .
No . Look at me . Can I just say one more thing ?
I 'm not gonna say , you know , " There 's plenty more fish in the sea . " "
I 'm not gonna say , " If you love her let her go . "
And I 'm not gonna bombard you with clichés .
But what I will say is this ,
" It 's not the end of the world . "
( BANGING )
Sorry , we 're closed .
Pisshead .
( HUMMING )
- ( SINGING ) Bass - Bass
( BOTH HARMONIZING )
- White lines . Visions , dreams of passion - White lines . Visions , dreams of passion
- Blowing through my mind - Blowing through my mind
- And all the while I think of you . High ... - And all the while I think of you . High ...
ED : What 's wrong , haven 't you had your tea ?
- Something of a phenomenon , baby - Something of a phenomenon , baby
- Telling my body to come along - Telling my body to come along
- 'Cause white lines - 'Cause white lines
- Blow away - Blow away
( HUSHING )
Blow
( HARMONIZING )
Get higher , baby
Get higher , girl
( HARMONIZING )
( GROANS )
( BOTH HUMMING )
- What 's he doing ? - He should say " Bass . "
Or " Freeze . "
What a tit .
( ELECTRONIC MUSIC PLAYING ON RECORD PLAYER )
You wanna dance ?
( SCRATCHING ON RECORD )
Hey , don 't scratch it ! Wait .
That was the second album I ever bought !
It 's 4 : 00 in the fucking morning !
- It 's Saturday ! - No , it 's not . It 's fucking Sunday ,
and I 've got to go to fucking work in four fucking hours ,
because every other fucker in my fucking department is fucking ill !
Now can you see why I 'm so fucking angry ?
- Fuck , yeah ! - Hey .
Pete , look , I 'm ... You know , I 'm sorry .
We just ... We 've had a couple of drinks . We split up with Liz tonight .
Just keep it down , yeah ?
Prick .
- PETE : What was that ? - Nothing .
No , no , no , come on , stop it . We 're friends !
He 's not my friend . He 's a fucking idiot !
What 's that supposed to mean ?
It means , why don 't you fuck off ?
You wanna live like an animal , go and live in the shed , you thick fuck !
- Oh , leave him alone ! - Stop defending him , Shaun !
All he ever does is hold you back !
Or does it make your life easier having someone around
who 's more of a loser than you ?
- What 's that supposed to mean ? - You know what I mean .
I assume it was Liz who did the dumping ?
Sort your fucking life out , mate !
What 's up with your hand , man ?
- I got mugged on the way home from work . - By who ?
I don 't know , some crackheads or something . One of them bit me .
Why did they bite you ?
I don 't know . I didn 't stop to ask them !
Now , I 've got a splitting headache and your stupid hip-hop isn 't helping .
And the front door is open again !
( DOOR SLAMS )
It 's not Hip-Hop . It 's Electro . Prick .
Next time I see him , he 's dead .
( ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS )
LIZ : Hello , Shaun , it 's me .
Look , I 'm gonna be a bit tied up today ,
So when you book the table , can you make it 8 : 00 rather than 7 : 00 ?
I 'll try you at work . Bye , bye , bye .
( ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS )
BARBARA : Hello , pickle . It 's me , Mum .
Dad said he saw you in town today and mentioned you might be visiting tomorrow ,
which would be lovely .
Will you be bringing Elizabeth with you this time ?
Only , we can 't wait to meet her finally ,
and also , I was wondering if she wanted anything special for lunch .
' Cause these days lots of people don 't eat meat .
- Do you want anything from the shop ? - Cornetto .
( DOG BARKING )
( CAR ALARM WAILING )
( MOBILE RINGING )
Nelson , have you got any papers ?
Nelson ? I haven 't even ... I owe you about fifteen p .
( GLASS SHATTERING )
( EXCLAIMS )
( MOBILE RINGING )
( CAR ALARM WAILING )
( GLASS SHATTERING )
( DOG BARKING )
Oh , dear .
Sorry , I haven 't got any change .
I didn 't even have enough at the fucking shop , so ...
Oh , dear .
Although no-one official is prepared to comment ,
religious groups are calling it Judgment Day . There 's ...
( SINGING ) ... panic on the streets of London
as an increasing number of reports of ...
SPORTS COMMENTATOR : ... Serious attacks on
people , who are literally being ...
NARRATOR : ... eaten alive .
Eyewitness reports are sketchy .
One unifying detail seems to be that the attackers in many instances , appear to be
dead excited to have with us here , a sensational chart-topping
or ideological connection between those committing the atrocities ,
and perhaps , more alarmingly ...
- ED : There 's a girl in the garden . - ... their behavior .
What ?
In the garden , there is a girl .
MALE REPORTER : ... the armed forces will be called in to provide back-up and assistance .
Scientists are still trying to establish the cause and nature of the phenomenon .
Excuse me .
Hello .
What are you doing ?
( ED EXCLAIMS )
Oh , my God .
She 's so drunk .
How much have you had , love ? Oh , I think she likes you .
- Shut up . - I think she wants a cuddle .
Listen , I 'm serious . I 've just come out of a relationship .
( EXCLAIMS )
- Ed , do something . - Wait there .
- Ed ! - Two seconds .
Jeez , look , I 'm really flattered and everything , really , but I just ...
( GROANING )
ED : And hold it there .
Ed , just get her off me ! Jesus !
Whoa . What 's up with her eyes ? What 's up with her eyes ?
Now seriously , Mary , I 'm warning you , okay .
I 'm gonna have to get physical . I mean it !
This is it . I 'm gonna ... Look , just fuck off !
- I think we should go back inside . - Okay .
- Shaun , what 's going on ? - Shit , it 's engaged .
- How about an ambulance ? - It 's engaged , Ed .
Fire engine ?
It 's one number , Ed , and it 's busy . Okay ? What do you want a fire engine for , anyway ?
- Anything with flashing lights , you know . - Are they still out there ?
( BOTH GROWLING )
Yeah . What do you think we should do ?
Have a sit down ?
There are reports of chaos on the motorways
as thousands of people attempt to flee the cities .
The M1 , the M3 , M4 , M6 ...
Do you think this is the same thing ?
... and M68 are all at a standstill .
The Home Office has issued a statement urging people to stay in their homes
and await further instruction .
Ensure all residences are secure
with all doors and windows firmly locked and barricaded . Police ...
( GROANING )
ED : Fucking hell !
SHAUN : Oh , for God 's sake . Oh , he 's got an arm off !
Get him !
Yeah .
( GRUNTING )
MALE REPORTER : More reports just in confirm that in all cases
the attackers seem slow and shambolic .
I 'm gonna shut the front door .
MALE REPORTER : ... receive information from the Home Office ,
regarding the best way to neutralize the attackers .
In the meantime , contact with these assailants is highly inadvisable .
Did you see his head go ?
If you 're confronted and have the opportunity to escape ,
( SCRATCHING )
It is suggested that you do so as quickly as possible .
- We should get out there . - No , no , no , no , we should stay inside .
- Come on , we can take them . - But the man said to stay indoors .
Oh , fuck the man .
Look , as long as they 're out there and we 're in here , we 're safe .
( GLASS SHATTERING )
MALE REPORTER : ... officials suggest that in extreme circumstances ,
the attackers can be stopped by removing the head or destroying the brain .
I 'll repeat that , by removing the head or destroying the brain .
( SHAUN WHISTLING )
Hey .
Aim for the head .
- Well , now what ? - We 'll have to get more stuff .
- What 's in the shed ? - I don 't know . It 's locked .
- Why is it locked ? - It 's always been locked .
Well , you know , we 're gonna ...
Oh .
No , no , that 's the second album I ever bought ! Don 't !
Now , some of these are limited ... What was that ? What was that ?
I think it was Blue Monday .
- Man , that was an original pressing . - Oh , for fuck 's sake .
- Purple Rain ? - No .
- Sign O ' The Times ? - Definitely not .
- The Batman soundtrack ? - Throw it .
( RECORD SHATTERING )
- Okay . Oh , Dire Straits ? - Throw it .
( BOTH EXCLAIMING )
- The Stone Roses ? - No .
- Second Coming ? - like it .
Oh !
- Sade ? - That 's Liz 's .
- Yeah , but she did dump you . - Oh .
- Oh , fuck this . I 'm going to the shed . - I thought you said it was locked .
- Which one do you want ? Girl or bloke ? - The first one .
( ZOMBIES GASPING )
MALE REPORTER : ... in all cases , people receiving bites
have experienced headaches and nausea ,
and developed symptoms similar to those displayed ...
- You 've got red on you . - ... by their attackers .
If you know someone who has been bitten ,
it is absolutely essential that you isolate them immediately .
The public are being strongly advised not to approach anyone ...
Pete ?
- Why don 't we just go up ? - Oh , no , don 't go up there .
- Why not ? - Because A , he might be one of them .
And B , he might still be annoyed .
Pete ?
Maybe he went in to work .
How come he didn 't drive ? His keys are still here .
Well , maybe he got a lift . He said he wasn 't feeling very well .
- Pete ? - Prick !
- He 's not in . - He 's not in .
- You got a fag ? - No , I 've given up .
- Since when ? - Since ...
Come on , babe . Oh , she 's engaged .
- That was quick . - Ed , this is serious !
( RINGING )
- Liz ! - BARBARA : Shaun .
Mum ! Hi . I was gonna call you . Are you okay ?
- Yes . - Yeah , well , are you sure ?
Some men tried to get into the house .
Well , are they still there ?
I 'm not sure . We 've shut the curtains .
Well , did you try the police ?
Well , I thought about it .
Well , are you okay ? Did they hurt you ?
No , I 'm fine , I 'm fine .
- Mum ? - Well , they were a bit bitey .
- Mum , have you been bitten ? - No , but Philip has .
Oh , okay .
- Has she been bitten ? - No , Philip has .
- Oh , okay . - Listen , Mum , what sort of state is he in ?
Oh , he 's fine . Bit under the weather .
- I see . - What 's the deal ?
We may have to kill my stepdad .
Listen , Mum , sit tight , okay ? You 're not safe there . We 're coming over .
- I don 't want to cause a fuss . - We 're coming to get you , Barbara !
So , what 's the plan ?
Right .
SHAUN : We take Pete 's car , we drive over to Mum 's .
We go in .
- We take care of Philip . - I 'm so sorry , Philip .
SHAUN : Then we grab Mum . We go over to Liz 's place .
Hole up , have a cup of tea . And wait for all this to blow over .
- Why have we got to go to Liz 's ? - Because we do .
She dumped you !
I have to know if she 's all right .
- Why ? - Because I love her !
All right , gay . I 'm not staying there though .
Why not ?
If we hole up , I want to be somewhere familiar .
I want to know where the exits are , and I wanna be allowed to smoke .
Okay .
Take Pete 's car , go round Mum 's . Go in .
- Deal with Philip . - Sorry , Philip .
SHAUN : Grab Mum , go to Liz 's , pick her up , bring her back here ,
have a cup of tea , and wait for all this to blow over .
Perfick .
No , no , no , no , no , wait , we can 't bring them back here .
- Why not ? - Well , it 's not exactly safe , is it ?
Yeah . Look at the state of it .
- Where 's safe ? Where 's familiar ? - Where can I smoke ?
SHAUN : Take car , go to Mum 's .
- Kill Phil . - Sorry .
SHAUN : Grab Liz , go to the Winchester ,
have a nice cold pint , and wait for all this to blow over .
How 's that for a slice of fried gold ?
Yeah , boy !
To recap , it is vital that you stay in your homes .
Make no attempt to reach loved ones
and avoid all physical contact with the assailants .
Do you believe everything you hear on TV ?
Yeah , I can see I , I can see it . It 's just outside .
Any zombies out there ?
- Don 't say that . - What ?
- That . - What ?
That . The Z word . Don 't say it .
- Why not ? - Because it 's ridiculous .
All right .
Are there any out there , though ?
Can 't see any . Maybe it 's not as bad as all that .
Oh , no , there they are .
( ALL GROANING )
Okay , let 's do this , yeah ?
- Yeah ? Yeah ? - Yeah ? Yeah ?
- Yeah ? - I got to do a wee first .
Can I drive ?
- What ? - I 've always wanted to drive Pete 's car .
- I might not get another chance . - Okay .
( GROANS )
( EXCLAIMS )
Oh , God . Sorry , Pete . Listen , we 're gonna borrow your car , okay ?
( GROWLING )
We 'll bring it back . And if you 're feeling better later we 're ...
We 're going to the pub . So , you 're more than welcome to
join us .
Pete 'd be so pissed off if he knew I was driving his car , eh ?
I don 't think so .
Shaun , Shaun , which button 's central locking ?
( ALARM WAILING )
Cock it !
( ALARM STOPS )
Get lost !
( ALL GROANING )
Drive .
WOMAN ON RADIO : The Church of England
has now joined other extremist religious groups
in proclaiming the phenomenon , a sign of a coming apocalypse ...
Dad .
... although Downing Street is refusing to be drawn into a religious debate .
Once again , the bodies of the recently deceased are returning to life
and attacking the living .
- There is no indication as to ... - Let 's put something else on .
... how or indeed why ...
( ROCK MUSIC PLAYING )
- What are you doing ? - What ?
Ed , look out !
( MUSIC STOPS )
I think we hit something .
Or someone .
( HONKING )
Are you all right ?
Come on , let 's just go .
Hello ?
- He 's gonna be dead either way . - Ed , that 's not the point .
( GROANS )
Oh , thank God for that .
( ROCK MUSIC BLARING )
ED : Ah , hello . Who 's a pretty boy , then ?
( WHISTLES )
You didn 't tell me Barbara had a Jag .
Oh , I 've always wanted to drive one of those .
SHAUN : Yeah , well , it 's Philip 's , okay ? And he won 't let anybody near it .
Honestly , I put half a Mars Bar in the glove box once ,
and he chased me round the garden with a bit of wood .
Fuck , it 's gorgeous .
Okay , well , it seems pretty clear , we should go .
- Why don 't I stay here ? - What , what , what , what , what ?
You know , just look after the car . If there 's any problems ,
( HORN HONKING )
I 'll honk three times .
Okay .
- Don 't forget to kill Philip ! - What ?
- Hello , pickle . - Hi , Mum .
- Oh , you 've got red on you . - Yeah .
Look , Mum , is everything okay ? Are you all right ?
- Yes , I 'm fine . - Where 's Philip ?
- Dad 's in the lounge . - He 's not my dad .
Oh , Shaun , really .
Sorry . Mum , look , I 've got Ed outside . We 're gonna take you somewhere safe .
But we have to wait for the doctor .
Mum , I don 't think the doctor 's gonna come .
I don 't think Philip 's going to want to leave the house , darling .
Mum , Philip isn 't ...
Put the kettle on , and I 'll deal with Philip .
- Okay . - Okay , then .
- Are you hungry ? - Yeah . No , not really !
- I 'll make some sandwiches . - Okay .
No fighting , you two .
MAN ON TV : ... you may ask " Where is our God ? "
But throughout the land ,
men and women of integrity rise up to confront the unseen enemy .
They will not be cowards , they will be courageous in the face of danger .
- I 'm so sorry , Philip . - Why ?
( EXCLAIMS )
What have you done now ?
- Nothing . - What have you got there ? Flowers , I hope .
- No , it 's ... Cricket bat . - Oh , is that for the jumble , Shaun ?
No . Yes .
There 's a box of your toys upstairs . I was going to give them to the jumble .
I took them all to the tip , Barbara .
- Oh , what ? - Shaun wants to take us somewhere .
Don 't be silly . I 'm not going anywhere .
Well , maybe you should stay here .
You know , wait for the doctor , and I 'll take Mum .
- But you said the doctor wasn 't coming . - You didn 't call the doctor , did you ?
Well , I thought we ought to be on the safe side .
I 'm quite all right , Barbara .
- I ran it under a cold tap . - I really think ...
We had our jabs when we went to the Isle of Wight .
- But , Philip ... - It 's a lot of overblown nonsense .
( KETTLE WHISTLING )
A lot of drug nuts running wild .
Still , I should get Mum away , you know , just " cause , in case they come back .
I 'm not going anywhere without Philip .
Mum , look , how about that tea ?
Mum ? How much do you love Philip ?
Two sugars , is it ?
I haven 't had sugar in my tea since 1982 .
Oh , yes .
Will you cut me some bread , love ?
Mum , look , how much do you love Philip ?
Oh , Shaun , do we have to go through all that again ?
Mum , look , what would you say if I told you that over the years
Philip 's been quite unkind to me ?
Well , you weren 't always the easiest person to live with .
Mum , he chased me around the garden with a bit of wood !
Well , you did call him a you-know-what .
- Oh , what , did he tell you that ? - Yes , he did .
- Motherfucker . - Shaun .
Sorry , Mother , Mum .
Look , Mum , did you know that on several occasions he touched me ?
That wasn 't true . Made it up , shouldn 't have done , sorry .
- Mum , you don 't understand , okay ... - No , it 's you that doesn 't understand .
Philip is my husband and has been for the last 17 years .
I know you haven 't always seen eye-to-eye ,
but I would , at least , expect you to respect my feelings .
You must be more adult about these things .
Yeah , come on , Shaun .
There comes a time when you just got to be a man .
I 'm telling you , it 's a fuss over nothing .
- Hello , Edward . - Hi , Barbara .
- BARBARA : My , how you 've grown . - Yeah , you better believe it .
What happened ? Why is he coming ?
It wasn 't as easy as all that .
- ED : God 's sake . - So , we 're following you , are we ?
No , it 's probably best if we ... Where 's the car ?
( CAR ALARM BLARING )
- I pranged it . - You were parked !
Yeah .
I guess we 'll have to take the Jag .
- Philip ... - What ?
Look out !
( EXCLAIMS )
PHILIP : Christ !
ED : Jesus !
- Philip , give me the car keys ! - You 're not driving that car .
Philip ! Give me the car keys !
- Ed , get Mum in the car . - I 'm on it .
- SHAUN : Come on . - No , don 't worry about me .
Worry about your mother .
- Ed , maybe I should drive . - Man , I 've adjusted the seat now .
All right , well , just , you know , be careful !
( ROCK MUSIC BLARING )
Can you please turn that noise down ?
Are you all right , dear ? Would you like another tissue ?
I 'd be fine , if it weren 't for that bloody racket !
- It is a bit loud . - Sorry , Barbara .
You do realize this is a 20 mile an hour zone .
Oh , yeah .
Here .
Okay , Mum , listen , this isn 't gonna take a second , all right ?
Philip , have you still got the child locks on ?
Safety first , Shaun .
You can 't ...
Hey , man , watch the leather .
Listen , okay , keep moving . If there 's any problems ...
Yeah , yeah , I 'll do the honks .
( GROWLING )
DIANNE ON SPEAKER : Hello ?
( ALL GROANING )
Hello ?
( SHAUN GRUNTING )
Guys , can you let me in , please ?
- What are you doing ? - I 've come to get you .
Sorry , what are you doing ?
I 've come to take you somewhere safe .
- We were perfectly safe before you arrived . - You don 't know that .
Well , there was two of them out there a minute ago . How many are there now ?
( GLASS SHATTERING )
- Lots . - Lots !
Look , believe me , it only takes one of them to know you 're in here .
Listen , I tried calling , I really did , but I couldn 't get through .
- I had to come up with a plan . - Oh , you made a plan .
Look , I don 't care what the telly says , all right , we have to get out of here .
If we don 't , they 'll come up here and they 'll tear us to pieces .
And that is really gonna exacerbate things for all of us .
- Shaun ... - Look , Liz ,
this is not about you and me , all right ?
This is about survival .
We need to be somewhere more secure , somewhere on the ground ,
somewhere we can stay alive .
- DIANNE : We 're with you , Shaun . - What ?
We 're with you .
I 'm not going out there .
Daffs ! I don 't want to be torn to pieces ,
and I 'm sure if you really think about it , neither do you .
- I 'm not going if Liz is not going . - Of course she 's going .
- Well , I 'm not staying here by myself . - You 're going , aren 't you , Elizabeth ?
- Lizzie ? - Liz ?
All right , Flash , what do you have in mind ?
Great , okay , I 've got a car outside , but it 's gonna be a bit cramped now .
- So , has anyone got transport ? - Yes , yes .
- Great . Where ? - Oh , no . Well , I 've passed my test .
David ?
I don 't see the point of owning a car in London .
Look , okay , just get any blunt objects together , all right ?
If you get cornered , bash them in the head , that seems to work .
Keep together , stay sharp and follow me .
- So , what ... What 's the plan , then ? - We 're going to the Winchester .
Okay ? Let 's go .
- Come on . - Where 's the car ?
( CAR HORN HONKING )
What 's up , niggaz ?
Okay , apologies for the cramped conditions , everybody , okay ? Di , stay on David 's lap ?
- Okay . - Philip , hang in there , okay ?
- Ed , get there fast , yeah ? - Yeah .
And , Mum , this is Liz . Liz , Mum .
- Hello . - Hello .
( ROCK MUSIC BLARING )
- Ed . - Shaun .
I know . Ed , be careful .
- Is your dad all right ? - He 's not my dad .
- DIANNE : He 's bleeding . - Yeah , I know . Ed , just be careful !
Thought you wanted to get there fast ?
( ALL EXCLAIMING )
I just want to get there in one piece , okay ? And why are we going this way ?
Chill out , it 's a shortcut .
But that road goes straight to the Winchester .
- Shaun . - Look , I know . Liz , please !
I still don 't actually understand why we are going to the Winchester .
Because it 's a pub , it 's safe , it 's secure .
- They know us there . - What makes it so secure ?
Because it 's got big heavy doors and deadbolts . You 've been to a lock in .
- Several . - And there 's a rifle above the bar .
- I would think that 's deactivated . - Surely .
It 's not . I 'm telling you . John 's connected . Big Al says so .
Yeah , well , Big Al also says dogs can 't look up !
- They can 't . - Can 't they ?
- No , they can 't ! - Of course they can !
- Are you sure ? I ... - Yes , look , the pub is the right place to go .
Okay ? Everything is gonna be fine , I promise .
- Shaun ? - I turned it off , all right ?
- It 's not easy . - What ?
- Being a father , it 's not easy . - What ?
You were 12 when I met you . You 'd already grown up so much .
I just wanted you to be strong and not give up because you lost your dad .
Philip , you don 't have to explain .
No , I do . I always loved you , Shaun .
I always thought you had it in you to do well .
And you just need motivation .
Somebody to look up to , and ...
I thought it could be me .
Would you just take care of your mum ?
There 's a good boy .
- Ed , can you pull over ? - Two seconds .
( ALL EXCLAIMING )
- Ed , please pull over . - What for ?
- Ed , just pull over ! - All right .
( ALL SCREAMING )
Whoa , mama !
Christ ! What the hell do you think you 're doing ?
- Chill out . Everyone 's all right . - Stop telling me to chill out !
And no , for your information , everybody is not all right .
BARBARA : What 's wrong ?
- Mum , it 's Philip , he 's gone . - Where 's he gone ?
- Mum , he 's dead . - No , he isn 't .
( GROANS )
Get out ! Get out !
Oh , Jesus ! Fuck , fuck .
It won 't open ! It won 't open !
- Ed , get the child locks ! - DIANNE : Come on , quick , come on .
It won 't open .
( ROCK MUSIC BLARING )
( SHOUTING )
Ed !
- Now what ? - We 've got to keep moving .
- How do we get Philip out the car ? - SHAUN : We haven 't got time .
- LIZ : What about the blunt objects ? - Do you want to get them ?
- Shaun , we can 't just leave your dad ! - He 's not my dad !
- Oh , Shaun ... - Mum , he was , but he 's not anymore !
- I really think we could ... - No , listen to me , Mum , listen .
That 's not even your husband in there .
Okay ? I know it looks like him ,
but there is nothing of the man you loved in that car now , nothing !
( MUSIC STOPS )
Let 's go , shall we ?
You 're not seriously suggesting we walk !
- Everybody okay back there ? - ED : Oh , yeah , we 're having a whale of a time .
Maybe we should all hold hands , like a crocodile ?
Do you have any idea where we 're actually going ?
- LIZ : David , come on . - Sorry .
- Do you , though ? - Yeah , totally , totally .
Well , are we close ?
SHAUN : We 're pretty close .
LIZ : Is your mum gonna be okay ? SHAUN : Yeah , I hope so .
Did you manage to get in contact with your folks ?
- They 're in Antigua . - Do you think this is happening there ?
I hope not .
Listen , Liz , about last night . You know , I know loads of things were said , but ...
Shaun , you said this wasn 't about you and me .
- No , no , it 's not , but , I just ... - You said it was about survival .
Yeah , it is , but what I 'm saying is ...
You 're not doing all this just to prove something , are you ?
No , of course not . I just think ...
Because I meant everything I said last night . Nothing 's changed .
( MAN SHOUTING )
Maybe this isn 't the best time to talk about it .
- Okay ... - Oh , my God !
Shaun .
- Yvonne . - How 's it going ?
- Surviving . - Hey , Liz .
- Long time no see . - Hey , Yvonne .
This is my boyfriend , Declan .
My friends Mark , Maggie , my mum and my cousin Tom .
This is Shaun and his girlfriend Liz .
- They 've split up , actually . - YVONNE : Oh , really ?
- Yeah . - That 's a shame .
Well , we should scoot .
- Have you got somewhere you 're going ? - Yeah , we 're going to the Winchester .
The pub ?
- Yeah . - Right , well . Good luck !
- Hi ! - Hi !
- Hello . - Hello .
- Hi . - Hi .
- All right . - All right .
( PHONES BEEPING )
See , what did I say ? The Winchester 's just over there .
- Over where ? - Over there .
Just over there , over the 20 garden fences ?
What 's the matter , David , never taken a shortcut before ?
( HOUSE ALARM BLARING )
Shaun , I 'm sure Jill and Derek live round here .
Now , the Winchester is just over that fence , all right ?
So , everyone stay where they are . I 'll ...
- Hang on , are we all here ? - One , two , three , four , five . Yes .
- There 's six of us . - Oh .
( BARBARA EXCLAIMS )
Mum !
I 'm coming !
Mum , Mum ! Mum , are you okay ? Are you okay ?
I don 't think Jill and Derek do live here .
Shaun ?
Are you all right ?
( EXCLAIMING )
( EXCLAIMS )
What are you doing ?
DIANNE : Shaun !
Yes !
No , that 's rubbish .
- Oh ! - Yes !
Feel free to step in any time !
- You did all right . - I didn 't want to cramp your style .
- Why ? - I 'm so sorry about that .
Right .
Okay , everyone just stay where they are . I 'm gonna check if the coast is clear .
- Is it clear ? - No .
- LIZ : How many ? - Lots .
Oh , well , that is just great .
There are a fair few of them , yes .
I trust Shaun has another genius scheme up his sleeve ?
This is hardly constructive , David !
No , Lizzie , this is a waste of time .
( HUSHING )
We should have stayed at the flat .
- Yeah , why didn 't you ? - Because ...
- Because ... - Because , because of Captain Wow !
Will you stop it !
Yes , we 're not gonna get anywhere by moaning .
( MOANING )
Right , let 's all shake out . Get nice and limber . Or not .
Now , take another look at the way he moves . Remember , very limp .
Almost like sleepwalking .
Look at the face , it 's vacant with a hint of sadness .
Like a drunk who 's lost a bet .
Okay , let 's try , shall we ? Liz .
( GROANING )
Nice , good vocal work . Okay . Barbara , that 's excellent .
Sorry , dear , I was miles away .
Daffs .
( GRUNTS )
Come on !
Okay . It 's mournful , sorrowful , you 're dead , and you hate it . Go .
( GROANS )
Much better . Ed .
- I 'll do it on the night . - This is the night !
( GROANING )
- What is that ? - What about yours ?
Who died and made you fucking king of the zombies ?
Don 't .
( GROANING )
- Yeah , that 's pretty good . - Okay , right .
Let 's all try together , shall we ?
One , two , three .
( ALL GROANING )
Go , go , go , go .
Shit . Get round me , get round me .
John ? John , Bernie , are you there ? It 's Shaun and Ed . We come in all the time .
- They can hear you . - We do the quiz .
- They know . - Stay in character , Daffs !
- I can 't see them . - Shaun , we have to get inside .
- Break the window . - Don 't be stupid , we 'll be totally exposed !
We are totally exposed . Break the window !
- Is there another way in ? - Well , yeah , there 's ...
( MOBILE RINGING )
Two seconds .
- Hey , Noodle . - You all right , mate ?
- Yeah , man , I can 't really talk now . - Did you get anything yet ?
- I got nothing . - Really ?
- No , I 'm right in the middle of something . - A bit mentalist , isn 't it ?
Yeah , it 's weird , isn 't it ? Oil What are you doing ?
What am I doing ? What are you doing , you stupid moron ?
- Fuck off . - You fuck off !
Fuck fucking off !
- LIZ : Shaun ... - I 've spent an entire life ... Look at me .
I 've spent my entire life sticking my neck out for you ,
and all you ever do is fuck things up !
Fuck things up and make me look stupid !
Well , I 'm not gonna let you do it anymore . Not today .
LIZ : Shaun ...
Oh .
- You were saying about another way in ? - Yeah , there 's a ...
What are you doing ?
No !
- Get inside ! - No , they 'll follow us !
- What ? - They 'll follow us .
Just keep up the act , I 'm gonna have to do something .
What do you mean , " Do something " ?
Hello , hello , over here , over here !
Come on , come on , that 's it , yeah , come on , come on , that 's it , over here !
Whoa , whoa , whoa , whoa , over here ! Yeah , come on !
Oh , bollocks . Okay , wait till I 've gone , then get inside !
- Gone where ? - Gone where ?
I won 't be long , I promise .
Come on , you pasty-faced fuckers , let 's go ! Follow me . Come on , let 's go !
Come on , this way , this way , that 's it , come on ! Come on . This way , follow me .
Come on , follow me . Come on !
Come and get it ! It 's a running buffet !
All you can eat !
Shall we go in , then ?
- Come on , Barbara . Leave those . - I think they 're for me .
- He 's been gone a good 20 minutes . - Seventeen .
Either way , we need to think about blocking up this window here .
We 're totally exposed .
- How will Shaun get back in ? - I 'm sure he 'll knock .
Oh , for goodness sake , let 's get some lights on here .
David , wait !
- Power 's off . - That 's a good thing .
We don 't want to advertise our whereabouts more than we already have .
- No , of course not . - Do we , David ?
No , of course not , Lizzie . I 'm just being proactive .
There 's no lights , there 's no power . Where are the owners ?
And there 's that bloody great hole in the window .
- You did that , you twat ! - Somebody had to do something !
I don 't know if you noticed back there , but we were in a spot of bother .
Somebody has to take control of the situation ,
and if none of you are prepared to accept that responsibility
then perhaps I should .
Will Shaun be gone long ?
- LIZ : He 'll be back soon . - How can you know that ?
I don 't think he 'd leave us , Daffs .
Wouldn 't he ? Lizzie , how can you put your faith in a man
you spectacularly binned for being unreliable ?
A man whose idea of a romantic nightspot
and an impenetrable fortress are the same thing .
This is a pub ! We are in a pub ! What are we going to do ?
I could get a round in .
Look , let 's just keep quiet and wait for Shaun .
We can barricade the window when he gets back .
What then ? How long ? Days ? Weeks ? A month ?
What about food ? What are we going to eat ?
- Toasties ! - Yeah , there 's a Breville out back .
Oh , great , then ! Saved by nibbles !
That must be why Shaun took us here before he buggered off .
- He 's coming back ! - Why ? Because he promised ?
And even if he does , do you think his master plan 's going to extend
to anything more than sitting and eating peanuts in the dark ?
What , is he just gonna stroll in and suddenly everything 's gonna be okay ?
I don 't know , David !
I don 't know any more than you do .
But what I do know is that we 're here now and we have to make the best of it !
- Ed , get me a double vodka . - Right you are .
Think I 'll have a drink , too , actually .
- Would you like a drink , Barbara ? - Hello .
Right , great , fuck it . That 's what we 'll do , that 's what we 'll do .
We 'll all have a party . How about that ? We all get completely smashed .
Oh , look , we 've got our nibbles . We 've got our Mini Cheddars ...
- David ! - We got Twiglets .
Oh , look , Hog Lumps .
- Pickle . - Hello , Mum . You all right ?
- Everybody okay ? - Yeah .
- Any sign of John and Bernie ? - We haven 't seen them .
- Check upstairs ? - I think it 's locked .
- What 's the phone situation ? - Dead . Same as the power .
SHAUN : Okay .
Nice of you to join us .
Yeah , well , I promised , didn 't I ?
How did you lose them ?
I just gave them the slip . Wasn 't difficult . They 're not all that .
Well , how did you get in ?
There is a back door , David .
I tried to tell you before you went and smashed the window .
Well , I wasn 't the one who was blowing our cover by having a tiff with my boyfriend .
He 's not my boyfriend .
Might be a bit warm , the cooler 's off .
Thanks , babe .
So , what 's the plan , then ?
Would anyone like a peanut ?
Why don 't you do your Clyde ?
Oh , come ... Has anyone seen Every Which Way But Loose ?
Ed does the most amazing impression of the orangutan .
- No , it 's not . - It is . Come on . Do it .
- No , no . - But it 's brilliant . Come on , just do it .
Do it , it 'll work . Come on , just do it .
You 've built it up too much , I feel uncomfortable .
- No , you don 't . Just do it . - DIANNE : Oh , come on , do it .
See . Everyone wants to see it . We could do with a laugh .
- Do it , do it , do it , do it . - DIANNE : Come on , do it .
I 'm not a performing monkey .
- The power 's on . - It 's not , I tried it earlier .
No , but the streetlights have come on . It means the grid isn 't out .
It 's the fuses . I 'll just flip them back on , we can watch television .
LIZ : What about the lights ?
Yes , we don 't want to advertise our whereabouts more than we already have .
The lights operate on a separate circuit , I 'll just flip the mains breakers .
It 's quite simple , David .
- Is that it ? - LIZ : That 's it !
( ALL GROANING )
( BANGING ON DOOR )
Liz , have you got a quid ?
Yeah .
Never anything on , is there ?
What ?
I think we might have a bit of a problem .
What do you mean ?
They followed me .
I thought you said you gave them the slip .
Yeah .
Well , we 'll just have to be extra quiet , then , won 't we ?
What ?
( LIVELY MUSIC PLAYING )
- Ed , no ! - Ed , no !
Turn it off !
Shit !
- Where the hell did he come from ? - I don 't know .
( UPBEAT SONG PLAYING )
- Who the hell put this on ? - It 's on random .
For fuck 's sake !
Okay , Dianne , get Mum somewhere safe . David , kill the Queen .
- What ? - The jukebox !
Liz , Ed , grab something weapony .
- ED : What about the rifle ? - It 's not real !
- Cocktails ? - What do you mean ?
The flaming spirits . Drambuie , Sambuca , brandy . Get a rag in . Light it .
- But the whole place could go up . - What , then ?
How about pool ?
Okay , John , it 's time at the bar !
( EXCLAIMS )
- I can 't find the switches ! - Well , then get the fuses !
( ALL GROANING )
- Why is Queen still on ? - We have a situation !
I know !
- Fuck this . - Ed !
Two seconds .
Oil
Shaun !
No !
Yes ! Yes ! In the head !
Shauny !
Why didn 't you just shoot him , man ?
Ed , for the last time , it 's ...
I fucking knew it !
What did I tell you ? Big Al was right .
Okay ,
but dogs can look up .
- Okay , has anyone fired a gun before ? - Oh , yeah .
- Apart from Ed ? - I 'm a pacifist .
Apart from David and Ed ?
Sorry , what was Ed 's experience ?
He shot his sister in the leg with an air rifle .
I think you should do it .
- I think we should all do it . - How can five people operate one gun ?
None of us have any real experience , okay ? Now , we 've only got ...
- Twenty-nine . - Twenty-nine bullets .
- Call them " shells . " - We 've only got 29 shells ,
we really need to work together on this .
I need someone to help me reload , everyone else to look out . I will fire .
As Bertrand Russell once said ,
" The only thing that will redeem mankind Is cooperation . "
I think we can all appreciate the relevance of that now .
Was that on the back of a beer mat ?
Yeah , it was Guinness Extra Cold .
- I won 't say anything . - Thanks .
( GLASS SHATTERING )
- They definitely want to come in . - Get Mum out of the way .
David , Dianne , let 's go . Ed , give me some shells .
- LIZ : Barbara ? - Oh , hello .
- Would you like to come with me ? - That would be lovely .
It 's nice to meet you , finally .
Shaun 's always talking about you .
- Really ? - Yeah .
Barbara ?
Are you all right ?
I 've got something for you .
Shaun 's father gave me this . Shaun 's real father , I mean .
I 'd like you to have it .
- Barbara , Shaun and I have ... - It seems only right .
( GASPS )
I didn 't want to say anything . I thought Shaun would be worried .
SHAUN : Liz ? DAVID : Here they come !
( GLASS SHATTERING )
SHAUN : Stay behind me ! Stay behind me ! DIANNE : There 's one !
Sorry , we 're closed !
( RIFLE CLICKING )
- Try the safety button . - Yeah , that happened to me on stage .
Cock it !
- Over there ! - Over where ?
3200 .
Over there again . Quarter to twelve .
What ?
- 11 : 45 . - Keep it simple !
Top left .
- Reload . - I 'm on it !
( EXCLAIMS )
Nice shot .
Okay , David , Dianne , let 's block up this window !
Ed , take over a sec .
SHAUN : What is it ? What 's wrong ? LIZ : Shaun , I 'm so sorry .
- Mum , what 's wrong ? - I didn 't want to be a bother .
Mum , I don 't understand .
The man in his pajamas ...
I didn 't want to say anything , I thought you 'd be upset .
No , you should 've said .
- Take over a sec . - DIANNE : What ?
- What 's going on ? - ED : What 's up ? What 's wrong ?
- What the hell 's going on ? - Barbara 's hurt !
- Mum . - Just take over a minute .
- Jesus . - DIANNE : I know first aid .
- SHAUN : Just hang on . Mum ? Mum ? - Is she ...
DIANNE : Shaun ...
Just hold on , Mum , you 're gonna be fine .
- I never thanked you . - For what ?
For these . " To a wonderful mum . "
It 's been a funny sort of day , hasn 't it ?
Oh , no , no , no , no , no . Come on , Mum , come on , Mum , stop it , stop it , stop it .
( CRYING ) Don 't , Mum . Please don 't go .
( RIFLE COCKING )
- What are you doing ? - We have to deal with her .
- Daffs ! - For Christ 's sake !
- She 's gonna come back ! - SHAUN : She 's not gone anywhere .
- Well , she 'll change . - She 's my mum .
- She 's a zombie . - Don 't say that !
Move aside . I 'm gonna count to three .
One , two , three !
Don 't point that gun at my mum !
Shaun , calm down !
Don 't point that gun at Barbara !
- Ed , don 't exacerbate things ! - What does that mean ?
This isn 't exactly fair !
- Here . - Thank you .
ED : It 's okay .
Please , can we just stop and think about this ?
Tell him to put the gun down !
Look , Lizzie , she 's gonna change . You know I 'm right .
And when she does , she 'll come back and she 'll kill all of us .
That 's what your ex can 't seem to realize .
That 's what this is about , isn 't it ?
It 's just ... He just ... He doesn 't like me !
He 's always hated me and now he wants to shoot my mum !
She 's not ...
You 've never thought I deserved her , that I was good enough .
What are you talking about ?
Oh , come on , we all know you 're in love with Liz !
That is not true !
- SHAUN : Yes , it is ! - That is not true .
- DIANNE : Yes , it is . - What ?
I know you only hung out with me at college to get close to Liz .
And when she knocked you back , I was there to pick up the pieces .
I 've come to terms with that , Daffs , why can 't you ?
Lizzie , I want you to know that my feelings for you have always been essentially ...
David , please ! There are slightly more pressing matters at hand here !
Like the fact that " Daffs " is pointing a gun at my mum !
I 'm not the one who 's being unreasonable , " Pickle . "
For Christ 's sake , she 's not dead !
She 's finished ! For a hero , you 're quite a hypocrite !
You 're the one that 's gone from being a Chartered Accountant to Charlton Heston !
- I 'm not a Chartered Accountant ! - Well , you look like one !
- Yeah ! - I 'm a lecturer !
- You 're a twat ! - Yeah !
She 's not your mum anymore ! In a minute she 'll be just another zombie !
- Don 't say that . - We 're not using the Z word .
Please , can we just calm the fuck down ?
Now , I can see what David is trying to say ...
- Thank you , Lizzie . - ... even if he is being a twat !
Yep .
And , Shaun , Shaun , look at me .
I can 't begin to imagine how hard this must be for you ,
but we can 't afford to fall apart .
Shaun , babe , I know you don 't wanna hear this .
You do it .
I 'm sorry , Mum .
Do it !
Well , I think we 're all agreed , you did the right thing there .
David , no !
( RIFLE CLICKS )
- David . - Right , I 'm leaving .
- What ? - I 'm not staying here .
- David , don 't , it 's suicide . - I think you should go .
We will . We can run , we can defend ourselves .
- What do you mean " we ? " - What do you mean , " What do I mean " we ? "
Opening that door now would be a very , very silly thing to do .
So , are you gonna stay here with him ?
- Look , Shaun ... - After everything he 's gotten us into !
You let me finish !
Shaun didn 't ask you to come here . You came for the same reason that I did ,
' cause you didn 't know what else to do . Get away from that door this instant !
- But ... - David !
I 'm so sorry , Dianne .
Maybe I 'm not the one you should be apologizing to .
Shaun ...
( GLASS SHATTERING )
David ! No !
No , no , no , no !
David !
No , no !
( SHOUTING )
David !
- Dianne , no ! - Dianne , no !
I 'm coming , David !
David ! David !
( GLASS SHATTERING )
Oh , dear .
- Cocktails ? - Do it .
Stay back !
Shaun , hold them !
Heads !
- Ed ! - Hurry up !
Shauny , look who it is .
Fuck-a-doodle-doo !
Ed !
- Shaun ! - Ed !
Don 't groan at me , you thick fuck !
I can 't hold them !
( SCREAMING )
No !
- Shaun ! - Pete !
I said , leave him alone !
Ed ! Ed !
Shaun , bar !
Ed !
( GRUNTS )
What ?
Chuck us a cloth will you ?
- Where are the shells ? - They 're on the bar .
Oh , fuck !
( EXCLAIMS )
Fuck it !
What are we gonna do ? Where are we gonna go ?
- The cellar ! - Maybe we can get out .
There 's a barrel hatch that leads into the street .
You mean go back outside ?
Oh , give us a fucking break !
- Go ! - Go !
( GROANING )
I can see the street .
Come on .
Come on !
Why won 't it open ?
That 's it , isn 't it ? We 're trapped .
" Hey , let 's go to the Winchester ! "
Whose fucking idea was that ?
Man , I 've really ballsed this up .
- No , you haven 't . - I have , Liz . I couldn 't save us .
I couldn 't save Di or David . I couldn 't even save my mum . I 'm useless .
You shouldn 't feel so responsible , you tried .
You did something , that 's what counts .
Yeah , I suppose .
( CELLAR DOOR CREAKING )
- Do you think they 'll get through ? - Yeah .
How many shells have we got left ?
Two . I suppose we could take a few of them out if they stand in a line .
- I wasn 't thinking about them . - I know .
What about Ed ? There 's only two shells .
ED : I don 't mind being eaten .
How are we gonna do this ?
I don 't know .
One of us has to go first .
Maybe one should do the other and then do themselves .
Maybe you should do me . I 'll only muck it up if I have to do myself .
( IMITATING GUNSHOT )
( IMITATING GUN RELOADING )
Do you know , I don 't think I 've got it in me
to shoot my flatmate , my mum and my girlfriend all in the same evening .
What makes you think I 've taken you back ?
You don 't want to die single , do you ?
ED : Actually , I would like to be shot .
Besides , I 've changed . I haven 't had a fag since yesterday , I promise .
ED : He hasn 't .
Maybe we should have one now .
- What ... - You left them in my flat .
- Yeah , in the bin . - I was desperate .
- Sneaky monkey . - Sorry .
I won 't say anything .
Come on , we 're getting out of here .
- I might just stay here . - Yeah , but we can get out .
- I think you two should make a go of it . - What are you talking about ?
- I only hold you back . - Yeah , but ...
Maybe you should have this .
Don 't you want it ?
No . I can 't hit anything with it anyway , I 'm rubbish .
- Ed , I 'm sorry . - What for ?
" Cause I was shouting at you earlier on .
It 's all right . I 'm sorry , too .
- It 's okay . - No , I 'm sorry , Shaun .
Oh , God , God . That 's not funny .
I 'll stop doing them when you stop laughing .
SHAUN : I 'm not laughing .
You better be off .
Bye , Ed . Love you .
Cheers .
I love you , too , man .
Gay !
- Ready ? - Ready .
SOLDIER : Section One . Ready . Zombies to your front . Fire !
Section One . Targets to your front . Fire !
( SOLDIERS SHOUTING )
- Oh , my God . Shaun ! - Yvonne ?
How you doing ?
- Surviving . - Surviving .
They 're taking us somewhere safe . I thought you two might wanna ...
- SOLDIER : Move it ! - ... tag along .
Is it just the two of you ?
Well , glad somebody made it .
Come on .
MAN ON TV : Next , we 'll hear the story of 10-year-old Enrique Romerez
who fought off the reanimated corpses of his entire family .
It 's all coming right up on Zombies From Hell .
MALE REPORTER : Six months on and to many the events of Z-day
must seem like a bad dream .
And as we now know , the phenomenon resulted from the use of highly
not something I ever expected as a newscaster to have to say on air .
" Removing the head or destroying the brain . " Incredible .
Dead excited now , to have a top band with us , talking about their work ,
for the charity Zombaid .
FEMALE REPORTER : The fact that the mobile deceased retained their primal instincts
make them ideal recruitment for the service industry .
As well as proving themselves useful in other roles , such as ...
MAN : ( LAUGHING ) He can 't quite get it . He 's fallen , he 's down !
I don 't see nothing wrong with it
but I know that some people would see something wrong with it .
But he 's my husband , you know .
I still love him , and I still got the ring on my finger , Trisha .
You go to bed with it ?
WOMAN : ' Course I do .
TRISHA : All right . Okay , you can 't understand why she 's with him .
Okay , what do you say to people that criticize you for being with ...
WOMAN : Well , they don 't have ...
MALE REPORTER : ... initial claims that the virus was caused by rage infected monkeys
have now been dismissed as ...
Hello .
What 's the plan , then ?
Right , a cup of tea ,
then we get the Sundays .
Head down the Phoenix for a roast ,
veg out in the pub for a bit ,
then wander home , watch a bit of telly , go to bed .
- Perfect . - I 'll get the kettle on .
Can I have two sugars , please ?
( EXCLAIMS )
Adventurous .
Actually , I might pop into the garden for a bit .
Go on , then .
Two seconds .
MALE VOICE ON TV : Player Two has entered the game .
Ed !
( GROANING )
Yes !
♪ Ooh , you make me live ♪
♪ Whatever this ♪ ♪ world can give to me ♪
♪ It 's you , you 're all I see ♪
♪ Ooh , you make me live now honey ♪
♪ Ooh , you make me live ♪
♪ Oh , you 're the best ♪ ♪ friend that I ever had ♪
♪ I 've been with you ♪ ♪ such a long time ♪
♪ You 're my sunshine ♪
♪ And I want you to know ♪ ♪ that my feelings are true ♪
♪ I really love you ♪
♪ Oh , you 're my best friend ♪
♪ Ooh , you make me live ♪
♪ Ooh , I 've been wandering round ♪
♪ But I still come back to ♪ ♪ you Still come back to you ♪
♪ In rain or shine ♪ ♪ you 've stood by me , girl ♪
♪ I 'm happy at home ♪ ♪ I 'm happy at home ♪
♪ You 're my best friend ♪
♪ Ooh , you make me live ♪
♪ You , you 're my best friend ♪